<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonge Academie | Dries Daems</title>
    <link>/tag/jonge-academie/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/jonge-academie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jonge Academie</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© `2020` Dries Daems.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hub549ed09b3491903d0e1e250e82c34d1_24308_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Jonge Academie</title>
      <link>/tag/jonge-academie/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipating life after the COVID-19 pandemic: Connectivity in past, present and future societies.</title>
      <link>/post/covid-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/covid-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>














&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-connectivity&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; data-caption=&#34;Connectivity.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Connectivity.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full text available above under &amp;lsquo;PDF&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Covid-19 pandemic has dramatically impacted lives across the globe and will likely have lasting effects for years to come. Changes will be most profound in the ways we conduct our day-to-day interactions with other people. How can we as scientists reflect on these changes, and inform our understanding of its implications? As archaeologists and historians, our first inclination is to look at the past for inspiration and guidance.&lt;br&gt;
But is this necessarily a useful approach? In any historical comparison, it is essential to distinguish similarities and differences, as well as to try and uncover the underlying drivers of these events. One could argue that the current event is so significantly different from any other in the past that comparison will be moot, or at least shallow and uninformative. Still, this does not mean that a historical lens cannot be useful. In this opinion piece, I will not look at specific historical cases, but I will use the theories and methods of the historical sciences to interpret the current situation and provide insights for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2020-present 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://driesdaems.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dries Daems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/driesdaems10/website/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
