<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Studies | Dries Daems</title>
    <link>/tag/material-studies/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/material-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Material Studies</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© `2020` Dries Daems.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hub549ed09b3491903d0e1e250e82c34d1_24308_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Material Studies</title>
      <link>/tag/material-studies/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron Age to Hellenistic pottery at Sagalassos and the surrounding study area</title>
      <link>/project/material-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/material-saga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dries Daems has been working as material specialist with the Sagalassos Archaeological Research Project since 2014 as part of his Ph.D. and postdoctoral research. Since then, he has studied the pottery material of over 50 sites from the study area of the Sagalassos Project. His work has resulted in the first typologies for Iron Age, Achaemenid and Hellenistic pottery within the project. Through a better understanding of the diachronic patterns of production and distribution of pottery material, he has also shed light on the early phases of community formation at Sagalassos and Düzen Tepe, as well as provided a better understanding of settlement patterns in the wider area.&lt;br&gt;
He continues to work with the Sagalassos Project, focusing on pottery material from Iron Age to Hellenistic times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current research interests are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transition from late Hellenistic to early Roman pottery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlement patterns and communities of practice in Iron Age times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The impact of urbanism on material culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
