<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interdisciplinarity | Dries Daems</title>
    <link>/tag/interdisciplinarity/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/interdisciplinarity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>interdisciplinarity</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© `2020` Dries Daems.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>interdisciplinarity</title>
      <link>/tag/interdisciplinarity/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability and Resilience in Past and Present Populations (SuRP&#43;)</title>
      <link>/project/microproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/microproject/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human impact on the environment has never been greater than today. The enormous drive of technological innovation and economic growth has fuelled the development of our modern-day society. The energy and resources needed to sustain these dynamics are derived from the natural environment. As our ecological footprint increases, we are now increasingly confronted with the downsides of this insatiable thirst for growth. However, the limits to energy and resources setting the boundaries for the development of social life have run as a common thread throughout human history. Ever since the 19th century, historians and archaeologists have been interested in studying the carrying capacity of societies and their environment, to varying degrees of success. The research group SuRP+ brings together young scholars from the humanities, environmental, earth and social sciences to develop new methodologies to understand the sustainability and resilience of past and present human populations. The group seeks to re-assess past and current approaches through the concept of social metabolism, encompassing the entirety of biophysical analysis of exchanges in energy and resources between society and nature. We will use historical data on, inter alia, foodways, dietary habits, production output, heating infrastructure, caloric needs, and agricultural and extraction technologies, to test newly developed methodologies. The basic premise of SuRP+ is that insight into the resilience strategies of past populations offers a suitable prism for comparing and interpreting contemporary issues in human-environment interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network for Agent-based modelling of Socio-ecological systems in Archaeology (NASA)</title>
      <link>/project/nasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/nasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Archaeologists today increasingly use digital tools to understand people and their behaviour in the past. Agent-based modelling (ABM) in particular has recently seen a rapid development in archaeology. ABM focuses on the dynamics and actions of individual agents that act autonomously and interact with each other and their environment. This technique allows us to develop formal simulations of behaviour in the past, and compare the results with data from the archaeological record. Despite immense potential, ABM is yet to fully mature as a methodological tool for studying the past, among others through wider dissemination among researchers and the establishment of standardized practices. All too often, researchers starting new projects need to ‘reinvent the wheel’ and build their models completely from scratch. A collective effort to address these problems is key for consolidating ABM as a standard methodology in our field and for leading the way for other fields using ABM. This research network, funded by the FWO for the period 2020-2024 under the coordination of Dr. Dries Daems, brings together an international, interdisciplinary group of researchers to collect and compile ABM code elements and organise them as an openly accessible modelling library. These ABM elements will be curated, documented and formatted so that they can be used as base modules for more elaborate and case-driven models and research questions. Over the next five years, the network will be holding working meetings and organise international symposia to develop best practices and code modules, and make these available through the open model library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability and Resilience in Past and Present Populations (SuRP&#43;)</title>
      <link>/project/surp&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/surp&#43;/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human impact on the environment has never been greater than today. The enormous drive of technological innovation and economic growth has fuelled the development of our modern-day society. The energy and resources needed to sustain these dynamics are derived from the natural environment. As our ecological footprint increases, we are now increasingly confronted with the downsides of this insatiable thirst for growth. However, the limits to energy and resources setting the boundaries for the development of social life have run as a common thread throughout human history. Ever since the 19th century, historians and archaeologists have been interested in studying the carrying capacity of societies and their environment, to varying degrees of success. The research group SuRP+ brings together young scholars from the humanities, environmental, earth and social sciences to develop new methodologies to understand the sustainability and resilience of past and present human populations. The group seeks to re-assess past and current approaches through the concept of social metabolism, encompassing the entirety of biophysical analysis of exchanges in energy and resources between society and nature. We will use historical data on, inter alia, foodways, dietary habits, production output, heating infrastructure, caloric needs, and agricultural and extraction technologies, to test newly developed methodologies. The basic premise of SuRP+ is that insight into the resilience strategies of past populations offers a suitable prism for comparing and interpreting contemporary issues in human-environment interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
